<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title> - jelly&#x27;s inane ramblings</title>
	<link href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Spondolix &amp; Videos</title>
		<published>2022-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/donationannouncement/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/donationannouncement/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! I&#x27;m writing a quick post to announce that - well, primarily, I&#x27;m not dead. Yet. After a few hospital visits and a minor-scale breakdown and some familial issues, I&#x27;m now out of the other side of it, although not entirely out of the woods. Apologies for my absence, but these conditions have been rather oppressive to put it lightly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;give-me-your-money&quot;&gt;GIVE ME YOUR MONEY&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, as you may tell by the new shiny link at the top of the site, as well as the oblique name for this article, I&#x27;ve set up a few donation options! It should, of course, go without saying, but I absolutely do not require any money and will never charge anybody for access to my content; Christ, even for &lt;em&gt;free,&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; this shit&#x27;s a rip-off, God, no. 
However, if you do want to sent a generous donation my way... well, first off, thank you immensely, and you have my gratitude. Secondly, just visit my &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;jellyfox.moe&#x2F;donate&quot;&gt;donate page&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to see the two ways I currently have for you to support me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, actually, I&#x27;ll spin you a yarn about them now, why don&#x27;t I?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-you-should-give-me-your-money-please&quot;&gt;(why you should) GIVE ME YOUR MONEY (please)&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patreon and Ko-Fi have been my choices; both are mainstream, both were piss-easy to set up, and both should be non-problematic for anybody to pay through. I shall divide my attention between both equally - I will be watching the space!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, as listed on both pages, you only need to give £1 to get access to most of the benefits. One Great British pound. That gets you:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Your name listed at the end of my videos (more on this below)
-Your name listed on a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;jellyfox.moe&#x2F;patrons&quot;&gt;thank you page&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
-Updates on the progress of blogs&#x2F;videos&#x2F;what have you
-The knowledge that I&#x27;ve not keeled over and died&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For £2.50, you get:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-The same as the £1 tier. Except it makes you cooler.
-No, really, it&#x27;s just the same.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For £8:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-You can ask me questions for Patron Q&amp;amp;A sessions! With the release of each blog post and&#x2F;or video, I&#x27;ll do an attached Q&amp;amp;A session. This isn&#x27;t to say that you need to limit your questions to the topic of each post, though; go nuts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to pay any more than that, well, you&#x27;re nuts, but you can. I absolutely cannot ever thank you enough for even £1, though - and even that isn&#x27;t required. I already very much appreciate the support I get on my content regardless of monetary gain, so anything further is just icing on an already mostly icing-based cake.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, what&#x27;s this about videos I&#x27;m mentioning?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;videos-posts&quot;&gt;Videos &amp;amp; Posts&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going forward (and indeed, hopefully going backwards), I plan to give each blogpost I make a corresponding video. This may simply be a blogpost reading with any additional thoughts I have as I read it, or I may get some friends in to discuss it more widely - it&#x27;ll depend from video to video. My blogposts will maintain an unscripty feel, if that&#x27;s a word? Basically, I&#x27;ll be writing them in the same freeform rambly way, closer to just putting my plain thoughts down onto paper as opposed to falling into scripting. This isn&#x27;t to neglect research, of course; it&#x27;ll be only the tone that is more personal, without compromising or skimping on any of the information where I can.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a way for me to simultaneously provide multiple methods of accessing my content, as well as providing a behind-the-scenes look, seeing as it&#x27;s almost guaranteed that a blogpost will precede a video post. They will be hosted on the dreaded YouTube for now, however, I may consider other options should I get shafted by Papa Google. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does not correlate to me at all having my shit together, I can promise you that now: my schedule is non-existent. On top of that, there&#x27;s other issues preventing me from fixing that - I am a sickly person with a sickly mother, living in not-too-great conditions, so I can only apologise for the inevitable delays that content production will suffer as a result of that, and I humbly request your patience in the event of anything of the sort happening. In the event that it gets too much and I feel as though I am unable to deliver you content at least once every three months, I will halt payments until the situation improves, as I would not feel comfortable simply taking money from you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this said, I appreciate anybody who interacts with any of my content in any capacity. Feel free to read me, watch me, pay me - or don&#x27;t! It&#x27;s cool, man. You do you, no worries. Only do what you absolutely can. I respect it, and I respect you. Just don&#x27;t touch me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Resident Evil 4 Remake Invoked The Exact Wrong Response From Me</title>
		<published>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/re4gotmedown/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/re4gotmedown/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Initially, when I watched the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=Wr4PGa1sHFQ&quot;&gt;State of Play on the 2nd of June&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and it opened with Resident Evil 4&#x27;s remake being finally announced formally, I was somewhat cautiously optimistic about it, and that was that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I woke up earlier today and realised something rather quite damning to that notion:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Wait a fucking second. I hated the Resident Evil 3 Remake.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, alone, is already something that should have shot any potential excitement I could have for the game in the leg. But, then, I got to thinking something else:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Man, but I sure do love Ressie 4.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, then, would be enough to ilicit a response of excitement, of hope, for a sort of longing for this new take on it?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Fuck this remake, I&#x27;m hopping on Ressie 4.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, I did. I played about an hour of the original Resident Evil 4 later. Which got me musing even further:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Why the fuck would I want to even touch some shitty remake when I can just play the stellar original?&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, boy, here Jelly goes with her pretentious bullshit!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, reader, a while of back-and-forth in a chat with friends eventually lead me to a conclusion - I do not like modern triple-A games all that much. Fucking shocker there, right? I only constantly drone on about how most triple-A releases in the past decade or so have been soulless cash grabs solely constructed to generate player numbers and profits for companies. But why is that?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;remakes-remasters-reboots-retread-recycle-retire&quot;&gt;Remakes, Remasters &amp;amp; Reboots, Retread, Recycle &amp;amp; Retire&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is likely my extended tenure as a member of both the &amp;quot;fuck-the-over-the-shoulder-action-games&amp;quot; club and the &amp;quot;oh-my-god-Kazuma-Kiryu-punch-me&amp;quot; club speaking, but I don&#x27;t think I&#x27;ve touched a remake that seeks to actually improve upon the original experience in any grandiose manner in years. I think the most recent examples that come to mind are probably shit like Mega Man: Maverick Hunter X from, what, 2005? And possibly Metal Gear Solid: Twin Snakes, although that&#x27;s less so an improvement on the original, and more so Kojima wanting Snake to fucking flip over a missile. Frankly, I think all three of these are often painted as some sort of bold step to make a given game more accessible to newer audiences, when in reality, they&#x27;re more often than not simply just cash-grabs to bank on a recognisable name, as well as roping in new audiences with the whole &amp;quot;perfect for beginners&amp;quot; spiel. Each one is execrable in their own ways, however.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t like remakes as a general rule of thumb as it is; I think that if you go in and try to change too much about the original, you will harm the original vision that the game&#x27;s team had, whereas if you change too little, why would you not just play the original? Or, worst of all, when a remake is based off of a game that is years, if not decades older than it, yet the remake does not retain all of the content from that original game, whilst changing just about every aspect it does retain for the worse.
Yes, that is me obliquely banging my raging hate stiffy against the war drum to sound out how much I despise Yakuza Kiwami 2 yet again. But that game itself is a totally different can of worms for another day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of a remaster, this is usually the more lax of these, in my experience. Yes, granted, it will require translating your code to a potentially wholly different engine framework, which will be a bastard, but most of the legwork is already put in, there. The only real thing required is to tweak and touch up a few antiquated parts, whilst ensuring that it is, at least, on par with the original.
And yet, again, I can&#x27;t think of many remasters that weren&#x27;t fucked up recently! The most I could potentially give credit to is maybe... Xenoblade Chronicles Definitive Edition? Maybe?
However, Xenoblade is a diamond in the rough; more often than not, you get things like the Silent Hill HD Collection or Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy - Definitive Edition. 
And, to be blunt, if you have the absolute &lt;em&gt;gall&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to call something &#x27;definitive&#x27;, how about trying to ensure that it is actually, again, at least on par with the game that you&#x27;re remastering? In the case of GTA, especially, seeing as there was that bug in Vice City for a while where, in one mission, an NPC would constantly get themselves killed in-cutscene, leaving you entirely unable to progress. Great job there, lads.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reboots are likely simultaneously the most ambitious and most damning of the three. It&#x27;s something I find unfathomable; why take a pre-established series and randomly fundamentally change it to suit a new narrative? The series that you were burning to the ground already had fans, as well as years of world-building, games progressively improving, and generally a sense of progression amongst them. In the case of these games, things like DmC: Devil May Cry or God of War (2018) spring to mind: one is a bastardisation of pre-established characters in a misguided attempt to appeal to a newfound audience to follow trends, whereas the other is the (in my opinion) sandblasting of what once was the cornerstone of a genre, having any relation to that genre.
Yet, it is not only a frequent process, but a celebrated one to entirely forego the staples of a series, in favour of making an entirely fresh take? That sounds great on paper, but at that point, why not just do something entirely new? Speaking of which:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;stop-franchises&quot;&gt;Stop Franchises&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m just going to say it outright; the games industry is stagnated with the same series taking up too much space in the release schedule. I hate it.
I hate the culture that undoubtedly will always flock to A Series + 1, because they liked the last A Series game so much. 
It leads to higher-ups pushing developers to make the same things over and over again because they guarantee profits - see your Call of Dutys, or Battlefields, or however many other, for lack of a better term, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;vuNN1D-FCjs?t=300&quot;&gt;spunk-gargle-wee-wee games (thank you Yahtzee Croshaw)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; there&#x27;s been churned out over the years for proof of all that. Or, indeed, the aforementioned Resident Evils.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to know a great example of a franchise that should have ended, but kept going to chase profits?
Silent Hill!
Silent Hill 1, 2, 3 and 4 all have entirely unique vibes, stories, challenges and characters - at least for the majority of them. The one underlying thread to them all is, of course, their relation to the fictional titular town, but beyond that, each is different in it&#x27;s method of execution. 
And do you know why that is?
Because of Team Silent&#x27;s ever-changing line-up of employees. Oh, yeah, Team Silent wasn&#x27;t just a constant; it shifted and morphed between games, hence why the first four Silent Hill games each have such a unique air to theme. 
This is likely the best solution to the event of a series expanding in any capacity; change up the people working on it, like, a major shakeup, or make the games therein rely more on an underlying theme or perhaps even both; the example that I would most like to cite would be something akin to the Cornetto Trilogy, where the three films have interconnected themes and ideas, yes, but they aren&#x27;t embroiled in each other&#x27;s bullshit to any great degree.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another issue with long-spanning game series: there is way too much fucking baggage. Let&#x27;s say I wanted to play Resident Evil 6: okay, so I need to be aware of the conflict from the prior games, I need to know the characters from the prior games, most of the outcomes of the prior games... and there&#x27;s people who started with this one? Seriously, if you somehow managed to fumble your way into Resident Evil by way of RE6, I am so fucking sorry, you must have been scratching your head for most of the playtime.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hell, sometimes it doesn&#x27;t even have to be needing to know about them, sometimes it can be quite the opposite. The Mario series recently is massively weighed down by nostalgic throwbacks to older games - to the players who understand the reference, it&#x27;s neat maybe once at most, and to those who haven&#x27;t played the older games, these elements can sometimes seem antiquated. I remember having a conversation with a friend who said that &#x27;Throwback Galaxy from Super Mario Galaxy 2 is so unfitting, it feels like it&#x27;s from an entirely different game&#x27;, which everybody else originally laughed at, until we realised that they genuinely had no idea that it originated from Super Mario 64. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s one thing to have easter eggs in reference to other games included as a nice surprise, but to have outright levels or god forbid essential mechanics tied into older material is just excruciating nine times out of ten. The 2D platforming sections in something like Super Mario Odyssey are a great representation of this; yeah, sure, they&#x27;re cute a few times, but then it starts to feel jarring to go directly from full 3D movement to solely 2D, it&#x27;s weird to have the triggers be mapped to crouch in 2D, and it&#x27;s a departure from the actual regular gameplay loop to shamelessly ask the player &amp;quot;Remember this? Remember product?&amp;quot; in order to tickle that nostalgia bone. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, most games succumb to this at least somewhat, many of my favourite franchises have in at least some capacity - Sonic, Crash, Grand Theft Auto - they&#x27;ve all dabbled in exploiting nostalgia for their older products in order to net some sales, often to the detriment of the actual products themselves.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world, we wouldn&#x27;t be so intrinsically infatuated with Series A; we would be interested in it&#x27;s creators, and their... well, creative ideas. The reason that &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;findingyakuza&quot;&gt;I lament Nagoshi&#x27;s departure in my Finding Yakuza post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is not due to me wanting him to be stuck doing Yakuza forever, but for the creative spark that birthed Yakuza initially. I want to see more creative ventures from creative minds, taking chances to work on their passion projects, and actually having room to breathe and do so, with investments from triple-A publishers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, this is my obligatory back-in-my-day, shaking-my-fist-at-the-clouds type interjection to say that, wait, this did used to happen. Only, the last time it really was prevalent in a major way was arguably the PlayStation 2 era.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need more auteurs to be introduced into the mainstream industry, shake shit up a bit. Gimme some more Suda51s, some more SWERYs (&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;Swery65&#x2F;status&#x2F;1282804805140746240&quot;&gt;bless him for holding his hands up with the accidental trans misgendering in DP2, king for admitting fault on that shit, king)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, just give us some absolutely batshit creative writing, some talented teams behind them, and let &#x27;em rip, dude.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;concluding-thoughts&quot;&gt;Concluding Thoughts&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apologies if this all seemed a bit rambly, but I just wanted to blurt out a load of thoughts as they were clogging up my head. And Christ knows that I don&#x27;t want Yakuza Kiwami 2 or GTA Definitive Edition in my head for any longer than they have to be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I absolutely do not want to be the takeaway from this is that I&#x27;m some sort of elitist arsehole who thinks that nobody should hold any sentimentality towards anything, and people should constantly be flung from series to series, forced to make new shit constantly. Of course not. There are only so many unique ideas, and some people are perfect at one thing. Or maybe not, some people only have one good game in them, sometimes not even that. 
Furthermore, I won&#x27;t look down on anybody who enjoys these sorts of games - I appreciate that they do often help people discover what is, to them, an entirely new experience, and they may love it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I absolutely must make clear that I do not detest any of the developers or consumers of these games that are made in these ways. No, the blame for the state of the games industry rests squarely on the shoulders of the purse-string holders - as fucking always. People with money ruin everything with absolutely zero exceptions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, reader, there has never been a better time to emerge from the shithouse that is the mainstream games industry. There&#x27;s a world of indie games out there, unbound from the shackles of big companies! All you have to do to experience it is come out of the shithouse, walk for a bit, and go to the shithouse across the road from you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Namecheap Redemption Arc</title>
		<published>2022-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/namecheapyaaay/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/namecheapyaaay/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, dear reader, &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;namecheapaaaa&quot;&gt;last time&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the Eve Gets Fucked Chronicles, I was whining like a bitch about my problematic time with Gandi Mail. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so you&#x27;ll be glad to hear that fuck all changed with the Gandi Mail part of that post.
However!
One little addendum I would like to make, after the event: the Namecheap support team got back in touch with me! As you can likely tell, seeing as we&#x27;re back to jellyfox.moe, AS OUR FOUNDING FATHERS INTENDED.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So? What was my experience like with them?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh my fucking god they were so nice Jesus Christ.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously - I have had to interface with many a support line over many a topic, but never have I actually had real humans respond so quickly. Obviously, there was an initial automated response, just to confirm my ticket had been logged and such. But then, I got an email more or less straight back from a real, whole-ass, carbon-based, oxygen-inhaling, carbon-dioxide-exhaling human!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they were so lovely and helpful!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enquired within my original support email as to exactly &lt;em&gt;why&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; they had enabled 2FA on my account - especially since I hadn&#x27;t requested it. It turns out that it&#x27;s part of some sort of required push for security, as, in the words of the email, &amp;quot;it&#x27;s essential on the modern internet&amp;quot;, which I completely agree with. I&#x27;ve got 2FA set up with my account now just in case of any future incidents, however.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after that, just so I could get into my account and change all my shit across to not dead stuff, they disabled the 2FA temporarily and allowed me access to my account inside of &lt;em&gt;an hour.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; All throughout, both customer service reps I spoke with being the most cordial, polite and helpful support people I&#x27;ve had the pleasure of talking to. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, listen, I&#x27;m not saying that I&#x27;m a little bitch and I &lt;em&gt;cried&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; or anything over how lovely I found them to be, but... okay, yeah, that is what I&#x27;m saying. It was just so lovely of them to have helped as efficiently and as well as they did. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, on the incredibly slim chance that anybody reading this is from Namecheap: good shit. Keep that shit going, dudes. Your customer service actually made me cry with fucking joy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to the regular reader, I cannot recommend that you use Namecheap enough. Their shit&#x27;s fucking kino. Absolute doddle to set up your shit with.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why I&#x27;m Absolutely Enraged By Gandi&#x27;s Mail Server Offerings: A Rope of Sand</title>
		<published>2022-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/namecheapaaaa/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/namecheapaaaa/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the quick and impromptu post in advance, however, I simply must express my annoyance at the precarious situation in which I find myself at this precise moment in time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, to put that in the way I actually would like to, I am extremely fucking pissed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let&#x27;s start the story at the beginning:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a month or so ago now, a friend of mine bought the domain &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;mariostockimage.com&quot;&gt;mariostockimage.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, after we found that the domain was on sale for a relatively low sum of cash, and finding it quite funny. They decided to buy the domain using &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gandi.net&quot;&gt;Gandi&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which, to be fair, has been absolutely fine on the web domain front. I mean, you&#x27;d hope so, right? It&#x27;s literally just reserving a name in a DNS resolver, what&#x27;s there to fuck up?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, where the issues begin are with the mail server.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, when they were first establishing the mail server, they offered me an account on it as a sort of gift for my assistance on attempting to get the website itself to work - itself, a fruitless venture, due to the thing we wished to achieve requiring HTTPS, and frankly, SSL certificate generation was out of the question due to their hosting method, and they sure as shit weren&#x27;t going to pay Gandi more for their funny meme site that they got for like, $10. I snapped up that offer, as I found a great novelty in the idea of having my email address be jellyfox@mariostockimage.com. In fact, I found it conceptually fucking hilarious.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we sent messages outside of the server in order to check that the sending worked: flawless. We were emailing from our flashy @mariostockimage.com accounts, in the same way that somebody drives around in a flashy &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Peel_P50&quot;&gt;Peel P50&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but it seemed like it was working, dammit, and that shit was funny as fuck.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we come to today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping to change some DNS records in order to shift some things around to potentially host them off of an alternate machine, this website included. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then Namecheap wouldn&#x27;t let me log in, as it prompted me for 2FA.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, this already irked me. I am aware that it is a security risk to have not done so, but I had not enabled 2FA on my Namecheap account yet, nor had I any intention of doing so. Although, I can see why this would be potentially enabled automatically as a security feature. I fucking hate that it&#x27;s happened, but I can see maybe some sort of sliver of goodwilled intelligence in there, as it may have possibly prevented somebody from getting access to my account. A bit shit when that person is &lt;em&gt;me,&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; but hey-ho, whatever.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I went to simply get my code from my mailbox and move on.
I had no mail in my inbox.
In fact, I hadn&#x27;t even received the email back from another friend who I&#x27;d sent a tester email to.
I had been setting up my email address as jellyfox@mariostockimage.com on many accounts, many times, for many weeks. And not one of them had actually been getting through to my email address.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this our fault? Is this the fault of Gandi&#x27;s web mail service? Is it some other third thing that currently escapes me? No matter which weak link is to blame here, it&#x27;s fucked me right off, since I really did want to do some shit with my other machine today. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m currently awaiting a response to my support ticket from Namecheap, so hopefully I can get that resolved, but in the meantime... Jesus Christ, I am moving all of my email shit back to my ProtonMail address for now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anybody wants to offer me a free space on your mail server because you&#x27;re either really really nice or really really fucking deranged, drop me a line using literally anything but my email; Matrix or XMPP would be your best bet for the time being. Those can be found on my &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;contact&quot;&gt;contact page&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Rambling About Some Nice Self-Hosted Services</title>
		<published>2022-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/selfhostedramble/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/selfhostedramble/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes, you see people complaining about the quality of services offered by big corporations online. One of the most prevalent of these complaints is their servers, or rather their increasingly frequent downtime. Of course, no matter how good your server is, it will always need a wee bit of downtime, whether it be for maintenance, because the connection to it dropped, or whatever else. However, this situation, whilst understandable, is frustratingly frequent with services that many use for comfort - myself included. Such services include Discord, Spotify, Twitter - y&#x27;know. The usual suspects, really.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as a bit of a follow-up to my &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;whymakeawebsite&quot;&gt;prior blog entry detailing why you should make your own website&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, I&#x27;m going to have a bit of a ramble as to why you should give them all a two-finger salute and just do your own shit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;But Jelly,&amp;quot; I hear you exclaim from atop a three-necked goose, &amp;quot;why would I give myself more work when the apps are right there?&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, see, that&#x27;s the kicker - these don&#x27;t &lt;em&gt;have&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to be things that take more effort. Believe you me, if my dumb ass can get shit to work, there&#x27;s a good 85% chance that you probably can, too, reader. As to why you would undertake the task at all... well, did you not read the first paragraph of this post? It&#x27;s to mitigate as much of your own personal powerlessness in the event of a service going down as is possible, whilst also offering a few more benefits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, allow me to start with...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;navidrome&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https;&#x2F;&#x2F;navidrome.org&quot;&gt;Navidrome&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I&#x27;ve &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;movingday&quot;&gt;mentioned this one before&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Navidrome! Navidrome is a self-hosted solution to Spotify, allowing you to access any music you store on a server from all of your devices. It utilises the Subsonic API, which means that countless apps can connect to it incredibly easily, transcodes files as they are played as to not use 111,000,000 GB of your data to play &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=LQUXuQ6Zd9w&quot;&gt;War Pigs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and allows for you to have a fuckin&#x27; huge library.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img 
    style=&quot;display: block;
           margin-left: auto;  
           margin-right: auto;   
           width: 70%;&quot;
    src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;articles&#x2F;whyselfhost&#x2F;library.png&quot;
    alt=&quot;The size of my music library. Quite large. 700+ GB.&quot;        
    title=&quot;The size of my music library. Quite large. 700+ GB.&quot;&gt; 
&lt;&#x2F;img&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;I mean *huuuuge.*&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s incredibly convenient if you&#x27;re like me, and have a small horde of CDs you&#x27;re sat on, but simultaneously, you live in the current year and don&#x27;t fancy carrying a Discman with you everywhere you go. Just rip your CDs to your server&#x27;s storage and be done with it. Likewise, if you have a large, already-digital music collection - also like me - you can just set up Navidrome to use that and be away.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve been using this one for the best part of five months now! And I can singlehandedly say that it is infinitely more reliable than Spotify in just about every aspect, at least for my daily use.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only con that is really at all noticeable when it comes to Navidrome - and, to be completely fair, this is likely just my own stupid fault - playlists start to take a while to load after a while. That being said, this is when you&#x27;re adding, like, 2500+ songs to one playlist, so it should be perfectly fine for most people who aren&#x27;t complete data hoarders. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;jellyfin&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;jellyfin.org&quot;&gt;Jellyfin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Jellyfin is a bit of a recent addition to my repertoire; previously, I used to use Plex, as it was highly convenient for things like watch parties, or if I wanted to share bits and bobs with my family, or what have you. However, I started to look into alternatives around about the time that the Universal Wishlist feature was implemented; a means to shepard the user into using external services, some of which are even paid, after Plex itself already asks for a fee to have all of the features readily available to you. (Of course, I never paid for a Plex Pass, tight bitch that I am.)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it was on that search for alternatives that I ended up chancing upon Jellyfin; it effectively promised all that Plex did, except with one thing changed - absolutely no money required. You just start the server, feed it your media, and it will host said media with a nice-looking interface, posters, Rotten Tomatoes scores for your films and telly, all that good shit. To quote their own website - &amp;quot;no strings attached... your media, your server, your way&amp;quot; - that being a mantra that I would argue is highly essential in the self-hosting world. You should be able to own your media and watch in your own way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, coming from Plex, what does Jellyfin offer?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, like, everything Plex has, yeah? The nice interface? The theme songs playing when you click on programmes? The ability to share shit with other people? Hell, even the fuckin&#x27; DVR feature for the three people in the world who own an aerial that plugs into their PC? All of it&#x27;s there, dude, and that shit works flawlessly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jellyfin, in my limited time with it thus far, has given me very little in the way of issues - it has been a seamless switch to it from Plex, and it has performed infinitely better in most aspects, too. For example, remember when Plex used to make it piss-easy for you to install plugins before they started trying to grab as much cash from you as humanly possible? Jellyfin also has plugins, and has them in full force; more metadata providers, subtitle downloaders, and likely more... just I&#x27;m too lazy to have ran into them yet. As a result of me having access to lots of metadata providers, it was a lot easier for it to obtain metadata for my more obscure pieces of media (1940s Japanese cinema is a total bitch to scrape for), and as just a little cherry on top, the default, official Jellyfin player has controller support, which allows my slovenly arse to lie in bed watching Breaking Bad without me needing to lug my whole keyboard across the room.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only issue that I&#x27;ve ran into seems to be some sort of memory usage issue; after prolonged use, it may start to consume a lot of RAM - usually, it gets up to 4GB or so of RAM in my 16GB system at worst. However, this is something that could easily be fixed by using a cron job or similar to just restart the service every so often in order to flush it out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, similarly to Navidrome, this issue is usually not overly noticeable, especially because the RAM usage issue never seems to exceed a quarter of your onboard memory - yes, still a large amount, and indeed inexcusable if you&#x27;re using your main desktop PC to host a server, but if you have a separate server PC, or implement the aforementioned cron job band-aid fix, it&#x27;ll likely be right as rain. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;frontends&quot;&gt;Frontends&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having covered most of the big players in terms of hosting your own stuff, what else could be left? Well, how&#x27;s about some better, more private interfaces for some of the bigger sites?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to these being.. well, simply just frontends for other sites, I haven&#x27;t really got much input to give. This is more just a quick speed-listing than a comprehensive review of each of these; this isn&#x27;t to say that they&#x27;re lesser, of course. If anything, the fact that I have little to say about them should indicate to you that they do their job extremely fucking well, most of them exceeding that which they act as frontends for.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;invidious&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;invidious.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Invidious&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguably my most used site at this point, Invidious is a frontend for YouTube. It allows you all of the regular YouTube shite - accounts, notifications, subscriptions, the only real exception is that you can&#x27;t make playlists through the platform, although that sounds hellish to implement, to be fair. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a few nice added features - for one that&#x27;s been an absolute boon, it integrates a download button with a quality selector onto the video page. One that isn&#x27;t locked behind fucking YouTube Red, or YouTube Premium, or whatever they&#x27;ve decided to call it this week. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And another amazing thing for my uses: you can use the URLs in MPV, as yt-dlp&#x2F;youtube-dl will resolve them! And in addition to that, you can even grab RSS feeds for each channel that you like! It&#x27;s really just a better way of using YouTube, so long as you can eschew the ability to create playlists.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;nitter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;nitter.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Nitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A really fucking good Twitter frontend. It comes with support (and indeed implementation) of several themes, so that you may have the interface look exactly as you wish, on top of it allowing you to tweak more facets of the visuals. Nitter also allows for grabbing RSS feeds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, like I said - not a lot to say on this. It&#x27;s just fucking great, okay?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;closing-thoughts&quot;&gt;Closing Thoughts&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, all in all, I hope that my ramblings have been at least somewhat coherent enough to convey that I really dig self-hosted shit, and I champion this as a great way to both maintain your privacy, and guarantee that in the event that any of your services goes down, you can just go fix it instead of being at the whims of big tech and their downtimes. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dunno, dog, I just wanted to fuckin ramble, okay? You&#x27;re not &lt;em&gt;the police.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Twitter&#x27;s Dead, Move On</title>
		<published>2022-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/twitterisdead/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/twitterisdead/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, as you may have read, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.independent.co.uk&#x2F;tech&#x2F;twitter-elon-musk-buy-company-b2064819.html&quot;&gt;Elon Musk has finally suceeded in buying Twitter,&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or at least it&#x27;s close enough for it to not matter. This being the case, I cannot recommend enough for you to &lt;em&gt;entirely stop using Twitter if it is possible.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Seriously. This motherfucker wants to privatise Twitter. He&#x27;s another Silicon Valley douche trying to ruin the Internet. And the best response to the shitshow is to not partake in it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&#x27;t know why this is terrible, here&#x27;s a few to begin with:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It makes him more money&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He is notoriously up his own arse and will block and report anyone who disagrees with him&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claims to support free speech... whilst &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theguardian.com&#x2F;technology&#x2F;2022&#x2F;feb&#x2F;18&#x2F;tesla-california-racial-harassment-discrimination-lawsuit&quot;&gt;actually meaning he supports racism&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has used his Twitter account multiple times for stock&#x2F;crypto manipulation&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He&#x27;s a cunt&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, that all being said: what are the alternatives to Twitter? To name a few:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;reddit&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lr.catgirl.cloud&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, okay, yuck it up, but I&#x27;m serious; whilst Reddit may have it&#x27;s own slew of issues such as a general lack of braincells, a substandard level of self-awareness on display from most users, and most damning, it&#x27;s own involvement with NFTs. 
The main benefit of Reddit is that it&#x27;s extremely easy to find people who like the same things that you do; however, this can also be it&#x27;s downfall. Frankly, there&#x27;s been times where I&#x27;ve lurked on subreddits that are related to some of my favourite franchises, and it creates a pit in my stomach.
Although, the same can be said of the Twitter communities of said franchises, too; if anything, Reddit still makes me want to dry heave less frequently.
To access it, though, I would personally recommend using a hosted instance of Libreddit - the one that I have linked to above is an instance hosted via &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;catgirl.cloud&quot;&gt;catgirl.cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - also a hoster of a few other alternate sites for YouTube and, funnily enough, Twitter.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-it-your-damn-self&quot;&gt;Do it your damn self!&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep, time to &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;whymakeawebsite&#x2F;&quot;&gt;scream this one from the rooftops again.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; You want a good place to express yourself, post your thoughts, feelings, pictures, and all that shite? Get your own website. Hell, you don&#x27;t even need to self-host off of your computer, nor do you need to pay. Just get that shit running through &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pages.github.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;GitHub pages&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I can attest that it is far better and far more engaging to write a post that isn&#x27;t put under the arduous limit of 120 characters - 240 if you have more money than sense. This one&#x27;s a bit advanced, as it will require you to at least learn a little bit of HTML, even if you use something such as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wordpress.org&quot;&gt;WordPress,&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or if you really fancy learning the nitty-gritty, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;learn.sadgrl.online&#x2F;&quot;&gt;using Sadness&#x27;s guides&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to make your own site from scratch, start to finish. This way, the only issues with your website are... well, your own. Don&#x27;t like a certain element of your website? Change it. Want something new? Make it. It&#x27;s a fun process, although not one suited for everybody, which brings me onto my final suggestion:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mastodon&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;joinmastodon.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, as briefly mentioned in the aforementioned website article, Mastodon is an open-source, node-based Twitter alternative. And it kicks arse.
It&#x27;s basically just asking the loaded question: 
&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;What if Twitter, but good?&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
Indeed, Mastodon is an extremely great alternative if you want all of the okay-ness of Twitter with none of the bullshit. There are many communities to Mastodon, and when you sign up, you pick one of the communities in order to form your identity - sort of like whoever your email provider is bunging &amp;quot;theirname.com&amp;quot; on the end of your email address. However, you can still seamlessly talk to, follow, and otherwise interact with people from other communities with no hassle - you can even move your account to a different community at a later date, if you wish.
And one great part - most good Mastodon communities will have active moderation against racism, sexism and transphobia. 
Yeah. You know how Twitter &lt;em&gt;says&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; that they do that? And then they don&#x27;t do that, whilst nurturing that behaviour that they seemingly want to abolish? Yeah, most Mastodon community moderators actually give a shit about people instead of entertaining a nebulous force of investors, so if you&#x27;re a cunt to any minority, get fucked, matey. 
That being said, however, you may still discuss anything from cat pictures all the way up to highbrow political shit. Now, the highbrow political shit ain&#x27;t really my bag. However, shitposting very much &lt;em&gt;is.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; 
You can find me &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wetdry.world&#x2F;@jellyfox&quot;&gt;here.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, hopefully, that should somewhat clear up a few options that you could jump ship to, should you want to take the plunge and reject Twitter. Which I would highly recommend doing! It&#x27;s greatly liberating, and will hopefully improve your online experience, as you can seperate yourself from the swathes of children worshipping Minecraft or whatever annoying bullshit&#x27;s going on now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Don&#x27;t Get Overwatch 2 (as if this needed to be said)</title>
		<published>2022-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/overwatch2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/overwatch2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you may have already seen, Activision-Blizzard is at it again. Overwatch 2 is on the horizon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you absolutely should not be supporting it in the slightest.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, I&#x27;ve put off writing this because I may inadvertently give it some publicity to the few of you who read these posts, but I just feel that I must say this as somebody who passionately enjoys games, and used to enjoy the first Overwatch back when I was still an egg with no concept of what a good video game actually is.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, for the love of &lt;em&gt;God,&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; do not get into Overwatch. Leave it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The character tweaks are, at best, the bare minimum. At their worst, they fundamentally sandblast off anything that makes a character interesting to play in the original.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my example, Doomfist:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img     
    style=&quot;display: block;    
           margin-left: auto;    
           margin-right: auto;    
           width: 70%;&quot;    
           src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;articles&#x2F;overwatch&#x2F;coomfist.jpg&quot;    
           alt=&quot;doomfist&quot;    
           title=&quot;Coomfist.&quot;&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;img&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a positive alteration to a character. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is making a character fit into a niche that has already been filled in this game.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least twice over. In more or less this exact same way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, how many more shield tanks do they want to add to the game? We already had Reinhardt, then they added Brigette, and at least she was purposely added to fulfil said role.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is taking what was already an incredibly disappointing post-launch character, and removing what fun there once was. And in pursuit of what? No, seriously, I want to know what is possibly seen as beneficial about a rework wherein the thing being reworked is homogenised further when half the champions (or classes, or heroes, or whatever the fuck they&#x27;re called) in the game feel the fuckin&#x27; same. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a team passionately reworking a game to perfect it. This is a group of people desperately searching for things to change about an already overly stagnant concept in order to keep it afloat and warrant a sequel that has no need nor purpose of existing.
This is like if Valve released a new Team Fortress 2 update, but instead of doing anything meaningful, they just changed all the classes to Spy, or something.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I seriously cannot believe that some people are heralding such changes as the second coming of Christ, implying that they shall be such a great change that will breathe new life into a dying soul.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, for one - dead soul. Overwatch is dead as fuck and has been for actual years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, if this is &amp;quot;breathing new life&amp;quot; into it, then every time I exhale a new fucking galaxy must be born. This is not only clearly low effort changes in order to re-use assets and overall make it easier to create a new game on less work and money as to maximise profits for the big dogs, but it&#x27;s also making the game even more boring than it already is by, again, homogenising characters together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They may be promising and teasing all of these character tweaks, but I assure you, the gameplay will be almost entirely identical, if not worsened, and it&#x27;s being sold for full price yet again, built off of features that could have easily been added (or indeed, tweaked) in the prior entry. Because this absolutely reeks of the &lt;em&gt;Activision&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; part of &lt;em&gt;Activision-Blizzard.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what &lt;em&gt;else&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; absolutely reeks of Activision?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that they are so brazenly releasing what is (or was) ostensibly an incredibly anticipated game in a series that makes them lots and lots of money directly following the fallout from a scandal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern Warfare 2019? Released to cover-up the fallout following the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ign.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;2019&#x2F;10&#x2F;09&#x2F;activision-blizzard-hong-kong-china-boycott-blizzard-response&quot;&gt;China Controversy.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is no different on the surface, however, it&#x27;s actually far more insulting and soulless than usual Activision activity once you remember the controversy they are trying to dodge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A human life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A human life taken of their own hand, due to immense bullying, trauma and harrassment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A human life in the most dire circumstances, finding no better resolution from their situation than to completely end it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took a human life in order for Overwatch 2 to release.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you satisfied with that, reader? Can you seriously warrant a purchase, when you will be lining the pockets of those who are effectively murderers?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not forget what crime was committed to simply consume mindlessly; especially not for a product put together with such little care, passion and soul for anything beyond a pay packet. Especially one as execrable, lazy, needlessly delayed and undoubtedly soon-to-be underwhelming cash-grab as Overwatch 2.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you genuinely believe that you would sooner play this game than save your money in order to protest against the inhumanity of this corporation - the corporation who are already fine for money and definitely do not need be kept alive with tongue-baths and blowjobs - then please, close this page. Fuck off. I don&#x27;t want to associate with you. If you cannot go without playing fucking Overwatch in order to not align yourself with &lt;em&gt;murderers,&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; then I don&#x27;t want you in my life, on my pages, or anything. You are actively supporting such malice if you fund it, and if you do so willingly, again, fuck off.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apologies for making a bit more of a serious post, but I just felt the need to speak my mind on this matter. I seriously cannot believe that people are so extremely gullible as to fall for this shit. Please, for the love of all that is holy, do not support Activision-Blizzard. They are not worth your time, let alone your money.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Yakuza 0: Stupidity, Seriousness, Parity and Life</title>
		<published>2022-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/yakuza0/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/yakuza0/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Often, there are games with great stories, but terrible gameplay; the gameplay is really fun, yet the soundtrack isn&#x27;t there; the soundtrack tugs you off in bed, but the story goes for the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.urbandictionary.com&#x2F;define.php?term=viatnamese+landmine&quot;&gt;Vietnamese Landmine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a deviation from that norm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yakuza 0 is one hell of a game. Like, it fucking owns, so hard.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to play it some more at nights to wind down before I go to sleep. This then shifted to me playing it after I woke up, too. And everywhere in-between. I got sucked down the rabbithole all over again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But just what is so enticing, so alluring about it? What about Yakuza makes me go &amp;quot;yes, all of this, I want it, right now, in my face&amp;quot;?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, to be wholly honest, I can&#x27;t really articulate it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is a bit of a pisser, because that does sort of render this post a bit of a pointless exercise.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that that&#x27;s any different from my other posts, mind you. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned previously, Yakuza 0 is a bit of an outlier in this regard; it&#x27;s so expertly crafted in every department that you can&#x27;t help but appreciate it. Yakuza 0 is the quintessential Yakuza game, too, if judged by this metric: it has the best plot, the best music, the best gameplay, the best side content.. everything about it is just so good. Yet I can&#x27;t find one main thing on which I stake my enjoyment of the series.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The side content is incredibly wacky and silly, whilst still never overstepping the boundary into trying overly hard to present itself as such; and this is why it works so well. We get to see Kiryu, our protagonist and straight man, placed into these overly absurd situations, reacting in different ways based on the situation at hand - disgust at a high school girl exploiting her fellow students for her monetary gain, but a hesitant affection for a live chicken he wins when bowling, for example. &lt;em&gt;A live chicken which he then makes into a fucking business manager for his real estate firm.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Which isn&#x27;t played up, or anything - Kiryu simply receives a chicken, and makes it run his business, fuck you. In a lesser game, the protagonist would remark on how silly and absurd this situation is in order to force laughter, but Yakuza is so confident in how fucking stupid it is that it sees no reason to reinforce what is already obvious - that being that this shit is fucking wack, dude. 
&lt;img 
    style=&quot;display: block;
           margin-left: auto;
	   margin-right: auto;
	   width: 70%;&quot;
	   src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;articles&#x2F;y0&#x2F;nugget.jpg&quot;
	   alt=&quot;chimken&quot;
	   title=&quot;Chicken.&quot;&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;img&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;He even fucking names it &#x27;Nugget&#x27;. &lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Contrast this with the main plot; it&#x27;s a hammed-up, cheesy, melodramatic as fuck crime drama. And I love it. It spirals off from Kiryu doing a collections run that goes wrong, ultimately resulting in him being framed for the murder of the person he was to collect from. To make matters worse, the incident took place in a prime real estate spot: the Empty Lot - a space the size of a postage stamp, yet incredibly lucrative, potentially promising the person who owns it an exponential increase in revenue. The Empty Lot is on the police radar as a result of the death, and so Kiryu is subsequently forced to leave the yakuza, but he wants answers. Just what significance does the Empty Lot hold? Who is this girl that they keep referring to in relation to it? Who really did murder that bloke and set up Kiryu? Why the fuck is Kiryu&#x27;s taste in suits so god-awful? You will find all of these answers and more as you play through the game, and that&#x27;s only from our first protagonist.
&lt;img 
    style=&quot;display: block;
           margin-left: auto;
	   margin-right: auto;
	   width: 70%;&quot;
	   src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;articles&#x2F;y0&#x2F;judgementkazzy.jpg&quot;
	   alt=&quot;kiryu&quot;
	   title=&quot;Kiryu in the Empty Lot.&quot;&gt;       
	   &lt;&#x2F;img&gt;
	   &lt;br&gt;
&lt;center&gt;Kazuma Kiryu, demonstrating his poor taste in suits and wonderful physique.&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Our other playable character is fan-favourite Goro Majima; this game&#x27;s plot focusing heavily on what he did after the 1985 Ueno Shooting, and his descent into his more recognisable persona as the Mad Dog of Shimano. As a fan of the series, this is rewarding: the Ueno Shooting was already explored through the lens of the supposed perpetrator and Majima&#x27;s sworn brother, Taiga Saejima, in Yakuza 4, as well as his life after the event - to get the other side of the story and see what Majima got up to in the years between the hit and the events of the first Yakuza game is greatly rewarding to somebody who has played through the games prior to these ones. Yet, it still manages to be a compelling plot outside of that to new fans, as it follows Majima struggling to win his position back in the yakuza, as he is punished by being made to manage and run the classiest club in Osaka - The Grand Cabaret. After the club sees great success under Majima&#x27;s management, he receives one final job in order to get him back in: assassinate Makoto Makimura. Majima goes on a wild goose chase to find this person, originally believing them to be the God Hand masseuse of Hogushi Kaikan. This, however, is revealed to be untrue; God Hand is actually Wen Hai Lee, a former professional assassin turned acupuncturist. Makoto is somebody else entirely, leaving Majima in turmoil as to whether he can go through with his hit or not. Again, this sets up the plot nicely, just as with Kiryu, leaving us with many questions; will Majima assassinate Makoto? Will he get back into the yakuza? Why is his taste in suits so much better than Kiryu&#x27;s?
&lt;img 
    style=&quot;display: block;
           margin-left: auto;
	   margin-right: auto;
	   width: 70%;&quot;
	   src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;articles&#x2F;y0&#x2F;majimer.webp&quot;
	   alt=&quot;majima my beloved&quot;
	   title=&quot;majima my beloved&quot;&gt;       
	   &lt;&#x2F;img&gt;
	   &lt;br&gt;
&lt;center&gt;Goro Majima rocking a similar, yet subtly different suit to Kiryu&#x27;s, whilst also demonstrating his own physique. &lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Of course, there is a great contrast between these wacky antics and this somewhat serious (although undoubtedly not overly serious) plot: you can play as a hot, muscly man delivering a pizza whilst really dumb music exclusive to that substory plays in one moment, only for that same man to then go back to being embroiled in a murder mystery leading to him being framed and trying to beat the shit out of everybody in the yakuza who has wronged him, and then some. Now, whilst in most games, such a tonal clash would be an unwelcomed, jarring failure, again, Yakuza is an outlier; if anything, the game wouldn&#x27;t be as great as it is &lt;i&gt;without&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; the tonal whiplash. I love the fact that I can run into random people, helping them with their day if they&#x27;re good and in need, beating the shit out of them if they&#x27;re dickheads, using swordfish as guns (I don&#x27;t know either but it&#x27;s there?????) and just generally pissing about in a facsimile of downtown Tokyo.
&lt;p&gt;That leads me onto another reason why I adore Yakuza as a whole; the locations, especially the virtual tourism aspect. From the beginning of the series, RGG Studio made it their aim to attempt to make the most realistic depictions of the locations featured in their games as was humanly possible with the technology, and throughout the series, we got to see them evolve - both as technology was improving, and as the real-life locations were changing. This is flipped on it&#x27;s head, as Yakuza 0 provides us a look &lt;em&gt;back&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; in time, to an image of Kamurocho, the mainstay location of the series, in the height of the Japanese Bubble period of the late 1980s, where money was plentiful, lights were bright, and life was good. It is packed to the gills with arcades, bowling alleys, batting cages, karaoke bars, regular-ass drinking bars, seedy underground cat-fighting rings, shops, restaurants... everything that you can think of, really. As a result of how much shit there is, Kamurocho is incredibly densely packed: it&#x27;s streets are tight and claustophobic, it&#x27;s more open areas mostly being dedicated to roads, or to act as meeting spaces. It&#x27;s very much a representation of that very flashy, yet seedy red light district image brought to life, whilst also being incredibly loyal to the real life location of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Kabukich%C5%8D&quot;&gt;Kabukichō&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in Tokyo on which it was based.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;img 
    style=&quot;display: block;
           margin-left: auto;
	   margin-right: auto;
	   width: 70%;&quot;
	   src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;articles&#x2F;y0&#x2F;kamurocho.webp&quot;
	   alt=&quot;kamurocho&quot;
	   title=&quot;The Kamurocho gate.&quot;&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;img&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;A screenshot of the famous Kamurocho gate, as seen in Yakuza 5.&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Our other location is Sotenbori, a location based on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;da.gd&#x2F;QhhmZ&quot;&gt;Dōtonbori&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in Osaka, and one that&#x27;s wholly different in feel to Kamurocho; Sotenbori features a lot more open space in comparison to Kamurocho&#x27;s densely packed entertainments, a wealth more mom-and-pop styled shops, street vendors, book stores, and most notably, bridges! Indeed, Sotenbori allows us to take in the lovely sight of the Sotenbori River - at the bottom of which there is likely a new riverbed formed of corpses from the amount of dudes I&#x27;ve chucked off of the bridges over the course of playing these games. This river acts as the central point of the town, around which everything else is constructed: footpaths line either side of the river to allow easy access from one bridge to another, small restaurants line the streets, and generally, there is a bit less in Sotenbori than there is in Kamurocho. This is certainly not a bad thing: it is both accurate to the real-life location, and in a gameplay context, it also forces the player to consider where they go to stock up on items and such.
&lt;img 
    style=&quot;display: block;
           margin-left: auto;
	   margin-right: auto;
	   width: 70%;&quot;
	   src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;articles&#x2F;y0&#x2F;sotenbori.webp&quot;
	   alt=&quot;sotenbori&quot;
	   title=&quot;Sotenbori&quot;&gt;       
	   &lt;&#x2F;img&gt;
	   &lt;br&gt;
&lt;center&gt;An image of the illuminated streets of Sotenbori, as seen in Yakuza 2.&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The realism of these places is helped further by the use of real-life brands and licenses in order to make the locations even closer to reality - for example, the bars stock Beefeater and Jack Daniels. These places feel so lived-in, so real, almost breathing. They become characters in of themselves in the series; every time I step back into Kamurocho, I feel a warmth, a homely feeling. I feel like I&#x27;m exploring somewhere that I have actually &lt;i&gt;lived&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; before, as opposed to just a video game map. Dude, it&#x27;s gotten to the point where, nine times out of ten, if I boot a Yakuza game I&#x27;ve already played, I&#x27;m just there to bask in the vibes of these immaculate representations of Japan, and I barely even need to look at the in-game map to get around - I just now know the streets off the top of my head, where everything is, and so forth. When exploring, there is no soundtrack, you merely hear the hubbub and chatter of passing civillians. It is a truly breathtaking display of attention to detail, and a clear showing of the developers&#x27; passion for their craft and for their country.
&lt;p&gt;The way that all of these facets combine hammers home a message constantly hammered in by the series, both in side content and in the main game: life can be a bitch, but it&#x27;s also very beautiful at times. Yes, Kiryu and Majima may both be pushed into terrible situations, but they don&#x27;t allow it to stop them from acting, nor do they let themselves wallow in their lower moments; they keep going, for what they believe in, for who they love, for justice. And it is &lt;em&gt;so fucking corny.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; And I &lt;em&gt;fucking&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;love it.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
It&#x27;s why I can get so easily invested in these games. Relatability. We may not be able to directly relate to the position Kiryu or Majima are in, yes, but we can emphathise with them, we see their emotions get the better of them, we see them be &lt;em&gt;people, living their lives.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...Too pretentious? Yeah, alright, I&#x27;ll wind down.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the tone and atmosphere of Yakuza 0 is a masterclass in balancing the gritty with the absurd, the silly with the serious and the mental with the menial. This is a great contributing factor as to why I adore it so god-damned much, along with the rest of the series prior to this game. I haven&#x27;t even scratched the surface on the characters, their relationships, and why I fucking adore them, but frankly, I think I&#x27;d get RSI attempting to do so within this already incredibly beefy post. If you did read all of this stupid dumbass gushing and nerding out, thank you very much. Have a nice picture of a cat.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img 
    style=&quot;display: block;
           margin-left: auto;
	   margin-right: auto;
	   width: 70%;&quot;
	   src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;articles&#x2F;y0&#x2F;kitty.jpg&quot;
	   alt=&quot;kitty :)&quot;
	   title=&quot;kitty :)&quot;&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;img&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;kitty :)&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Moving Day (for my web content that is)</title>
		<published>2022-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/movingday/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/movingday/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yes, as you may have seen, namely by the big piss-off message staring you in the face prior to you clicking on this link, I rather recently decided to take the plunge and port all of the stuff over from my old Neocities page. Now, you may be asking yourself: why?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would I want to shift to self-hosting as opposed to using Neocities?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is shockingly simple, actually; it&#x27;s a bit easier for me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, true story.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already use a personal server for a lot of my stuff; I use it as my personal music streaming service (shoutouts to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;navidrome.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Navidrome&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), my personal &lt;i&gt;video&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; streaming service (using &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;plex.tv&quot;&gt;Plex&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), and I also maybe occasionally use it for other stuff. Such as this very website!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I just figured: what&#x27;s the point in keeping all of my stuff on Neocities when I could just... port it to my own server? &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this new site a lot more than my old one. It&#x27;s a bit more minimal with it not having to load as much bollocks every time you click on it, whilst still maintaining most of the actually &lt;i&gt;beneficial and useful&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;  bollocks, namely the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;jellyfox.sly.io&#x2F;about&quot;&gt;about page&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which allows me the luxury of being able to just send my webpage to people who want to know more.. well, about me. Turns out, it also serves to make my life infinitely easier now I&#x27;m done transferring stuff, too; instead of me having to slum it out writing every post in actual HTML, I can write my shit in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Markdown&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; now, and have it generate my pages based around that. And even better, that allows me to eschew that fuckin&#x27; awful looking .html extension on all of my links that used to hang off like worms from an apple, and is just so much infinitely easier to organise. Who knew?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although, if you saw my &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;whymakeawebsite&#x2F;&quot;&gt;prior post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and wanted to hop to it and make your own website, and you&#x27;re like me (i.e. broke as fuck), I cannot recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;neocities.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Neocities&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; enough; it lets you host your own website for free, and the features that it offers for that low price are more than enough to comfortably start your own webhosting fun. And, if you&#x27;re not dirt poor, they have a premium option that allows you to host basically whatever the hell you want, gives you 3000GB of bandwidth and 50GB of storage, as well as remote filesystem support (which, please trust me, you will eventually carnally desire). All for $5. That shit is banging. Like, that is an amazingly good deal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that aside, though, I implore you, please, for the love of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;FlCch15FJnE&quot;&gt;the baby Jesus,&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; if you fancy expressing yourself and having some fun in a way that Twitter doesn&#x27;t allow for and hasn&#x27;t allowed for in years, make a website! It&#x27;s a project you can chip away at in your spare time between your timeslots of being ever-so amazing, you great person, you. It&#x27;s also great for nerd street cred, because not everybody hosts a website these days. Everybody else is just using Twitter or Facebook or [insert social media of the day here], but you know what? So long as your server stays up, websites are forever, motherfucker. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why make a personal website? *</title>
		<published>2021-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/whymakeawebsite/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/whymakeawebsite/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;* Legacy blog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the age of social media, why would (and should) you opt to make a website in lieu of major platforms? &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do think that, in a purely conceptual sense, social media is one of the greatest inventions mankind could devise; a free-of-charge portal to other countries, other cultures, or Jim you met in the Red Lion that one night, without having to travel, all powered solely by the device on which you peruse it? That sounds absolutely amazing, on paper. Until you realise that free-of-charge will not remain so forever, whether that be paywalls, or worse, companies beginning to harvest your data for their own nefarious purposes. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I&#x27;m no tinfoil hat wearer. I&#x27;m not saying that this is at all an avoidable evil, because let&#x27;s face reality, at this particular point in time, the Internet is lost. The web that was is largely lost due to the monopoly that big corporations such as Meta, Amazon and Google have in their respective e-markets. They&#x27;re household names - you have &lt;i&gt;never&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; heard your mother say &amp;quot;oh, hold on dear, let me SearX that&amp;quot;, nor &amp;quot;I&#x27;m going to buy a new coat from Trouva&amp;quot;. However, what &lt;i&gt;does&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; still remain true is that you can reduce your usage of these platforms in order to reduce the amount of data held regarding you, your habits and so forth. But what if that&#x27;s not enough to inspire you? What if you&#x27;re like me, cynical and resigned to the point of largely accepting the corporate overlords, and wanting to just have fun in our painfully short journeys to the grave so long as they don&#x27;t take the piss &lt;i&gt;too&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; much? What else could possibly drive somebody to up and make their own website from scratch? Well, other people, of course. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;quot;But Jelly!&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; I hear the voices in my head shriek yet again, &lt;i&gt;&amp;quot;I thought you said that the fact that you can connect to other people was a great thing?&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; Well, you entirely non-existant viewpoint, that was in theory, too. As with the ability to talk to the few great people in this world, comes the ability to meet the rest of them. Those who are rude, obnoxious, abrasive, potentially even dangerous, or just flat-out annoying. And, of course, I refer to Twitter mainly with this. Twitter is a hive of scum and villainy that breeds only depression and loneliness; the moments of laughter from the increasingly rare funny post are drowned out by the countless meaningless posts about somebody not liking something with zero reasoning behind it, the cancelling of somebody because they said something they shouldn&#x27;t have whilst ignoring their apologies and attempts to fix the situation, and lastly, the stan culture. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stan culture, conversely to the nature of the platforms on which it&#x27;s housed, is antisocial, as well as parasocial. Whether it be absconding somebody of blame of things that they very evidently did because you like them, whilst attacking others for calling them out, or following the person&#x27;s activities religiously to the point where it becomes your personality trait, or- Look, let&#x27;s just cut to the fucking chase, here - I&#x27;m sick to death of Dream and K-Pop stans - Dream stans being the more offensive of the two. K-Pop stans may have had the classic moment of saying that Etika wouldn&#x27;t have died if he stanned LOONA (I attempted to search for the source of this - turns out all the accounts I could find linked to the original serious one have been suspended, go figure!), but those are just words, at the end of the day. Granted, words that should under no circumstance form in anyone&#x27;s mind save for if the person they&#x27;re targetting was, like, the reanimation of Fidel Castro or something, but simply words regardless. Whereas Dream stans often venture into far... how to say it... extreme territories. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t exactly wish to go &lt;i&gt;too&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; in-depth, but just to skim, in case you&#x27;re not already aware - many members of Dream&#x27;s community take part in a parasocial relationship with him constantly posting tweets that only exacerbate this, especially on his private Twitter (which, for obvious reasons, I cannot particularly easily link to or show you. Search if you&#x27;re interested). On top of this, he continuously uses these fans to get things: the &lt;i&gt;2020 Minecraft Mob Vote&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; is likely the one of these that&#x27;s the most prevalent in popular memory, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;dreamwastaken&#x2F;status&#x2F;1447264552660439049&quot;&gt;which he thought was a great basis for a joke when the 2021 one rolled around.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; In brief, in case you missed it, the &lt;i&gt;Mob Vote&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; was rigged by Dream alongside his legion of stans in order to throw the poll in favour of the Glow Squid - a mob which served no practical purpose even in theory, and in implementation has went on to be even more disappointing than anticipated. And why did he do it? Because he can. These fans are all so obsessed with the bloke that they&#x27;ll do anything. Whilst most celebrities, and indeed e-celebrities, would likely tell these crazies either to politely back down or to just straight-up fuck off, Dream opts to weaponise this in his favour when he sees fit; after all, if he can bounce back from one of the biggest video game cheating scandals since [name redacted to avoid lawsuit]&#x27;s blatant cheating in &lt;i&gt;Donkey Kong&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;, having evidence presented of him saying slurs, and have his blatant manipulation of them all go over their heads, whilst making a fair bit of bank doing so, why wouldn&#x27;t he? And of course, his stans won&#x27;t allow anything to be said &lt;i&gt;against&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; him - no, no, no! If you at all even begin to insinuate that you don&#x27;t like the man, you&#x27;ll be subject to thousands of the little fuckers in your inbox telling you that you&#x27;re wrong. This is without even scratching the surface on Poppy Twitter, a sub-community wherein such lovely, light topics as: &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;warning! not very nice things inside.&lt;&#x2F;summary&gt;
  rape, incest, underage, gore fantasies and&#x2F;or CP. I&#x27;m sure there&#x27;s far more alleys of degeneracy I&#x27;ve been fortunate enough to have skirted around, but rest assured that this stuff is decently spread, like, a fair bit. For the sake of your own sanity (and so you don&#x27;t get put on a watchlist), do not enquire further. It&#x27;s not worth it. 
&lt;&#x2F;details&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To clarify, however, I have no issue with &lt;i&gt;fans&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;, fans being people who like the thing enough to possibly consider it worthy of a mention on an About Me page or some such. For example, I&#x27;d classify myself as a &lt;i&gt;Yakuza&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; fan, since I bloody love those games and could talk about them all day. &lt;i&gt;Stans&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;, conversely, are a portmanteau of &#x27;stalker&#x27; and &#x27;fan&#x27; - in essence, they are so obsessive that their personality is often moulded around their interests. This would be like if I entered a steakhouse and exclaimed, &lt;i&gt;&amp;quot;Wow! Just like Wild Jackson from Yakuza 0!&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; without a trace of irony before attempting to triangulate Takaya Kuroda&#x27;s location through a reflection in his sunglasses or something. Stans are often dangerous, both to themselves and others, as they may doxx others that they disagree with, or sometimes even the person that they obsess over - &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.dexerto.com&#x2F;entertainment&#x2F;ddream%20twitteream-doxed-by-twitch-fans-after-posting-photos-of-his-kitchen-1488325&#x2F;&quot;&gt;funnily enough, the latter being the case with Dream himself.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;  These stans, however, are increasingly frequent, to the point where it is virtually impossible to go a day without seeing something related to one of the members of his &lt;i&gt;Minecraft&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; server breathing or some bollocks on the Trending tab on Twitter. They never shut the fuck up, and you can never escape a day without seeing at least one of them, like cockroaches with subwoofers on their backs reciting &lt;i&gt;Mask&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thus is displayed the glory of the personal website. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You don&#x27;t &lt;i&gt;have&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; to have the annoying people there. Fuck, you can entirely forego comments, not leave any links to ways to contact you at all, and so forth! And you choose exactly what you do and don&#x27;t want on your website: me, I want to make a nice, fun little place where I can talk about whatever shit takes my fancy on that day in particular, in as much length as I want. No character limits on HTML! &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;qOVLUiha1B8?t=32&quot;&gt; The only limit is your limited imagination!&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Look at that shit! I linked something inside of my words! Look, look, look - watch this, watch this:&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img 
    style=&quot;display: block; 
           margin-left: auto;
           margin-right: auto;
           width: 70%;&quot;
    src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;articles&#x2F;b4&#x2F;dog.jpg&quot; 
    alt=&quot;doggy :)&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;img&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Peep this dog!&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;center&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And I can add that &lt;i&gt;into&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; the thing I&#x27;m saying! Like, between my words and shit! And I can write &lt;b&gt;words&lt;&#x2F;b&gt; &lt;i&gt;all&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; &lt;u&gt;weird!&lt;&#x2F;u&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I have entire control over what I say and show, look - bums! See? Nobody&#x27;s gonna tell me off for saying &lt;i&gt;&quot;bums&quot;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; now! Bums! &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Bums! &lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Obviously, I&#x27;m taking the piss and being a bit facetious, but me point is that when you have your own website, you have complete creative control over what you want to do, what you want to show! You want to make a website about yourself, with your own blog, so you can ramble onto a page instead of pissing your friends off with it and killing the group chat for the umpteenth time? Go for it! You want to make a portfolio for commissions showing all of your artwork? The artiste in you will have a field day designing it all! You want to make a chatroom made for lovers of... I don&#x27;t fuckin&#x27; know, children&#x27;s breakfast cereals? Sail away, Captain Crunch, but you&#x27;re buying the next pint of milk. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And the best part, it stimulates yer head-hole! With Twitter, shite&#x27;s already there for you, innit? Either you scroll through the dogshit that&#x27;s there, or you add to the smell - maybe you might sometimes attach a picture of the cat stealing your kebab again, the pilfering bastard. With a website, you have to &lt;i&gt;commit&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; to your pages, you have to tweak everything, get it just so, make sure that the background looks proper, or that your font is the one you want, or what have you! It&#x27;s not just a simple case of &lt;i&gt;I&#x27;m bored whilst I&#x27;m having my hazy morning slash, I suppose I&#x27;ll Tweet something&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; - you have to put in the work to get to that point! This whole process has been an amazing little learning experience for me, and one that I implore that anyone even remotely interested in representing themselves online explores. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m not saying that it&#x27;s something &lt;i&gt;for everyone&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;, by any means - if you still feel comfy using Twitter, go for it - but it&#x27;s certainly something that &lt;i&gt;everyone can do&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;. If you want to escape the wretched hellhole that is Twitter whilst still having a place to express yourself... well, I mean, probably give &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mstdn.social&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a go if you still want to have as easy a time as with Twitter and still connect to people, but if you fancy a little project, and you don&#x27;t mind experimenting and learning, you can make your own personal space, full of whatever you want, wherever you want. You can even streamline your pages by crafting templates - God knows &lt;i&gt;I&#x27;m&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; not re-typing the UI of this place every time I make a new page - and have the ability to just write. And that, really, is the main fun of it, to me: &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;You can tinker &#x27;til your heart&#x27;s content,&lt;br&gt; and you can make whatever content you &lt;br&gt;want. All without anyone to tell you &#x27;no&#x27;.&lt;&#x2F;b&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;hehe. bums.&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>For the love of God, don&#x27;t support J.K. Rowling. *</title>
		<published>2021-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/dontsupportjkrowling/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/dontsupportjkrowling/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;* Legacy blog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something that I absolutely cannot stress enough: please, for fuck&#x27;s sake, do not support J.K. Rowling. She&#x27;s made more money than any of us will ever make by making one of the most generic, boring fantasy series of all time - a generic series which saw widespread success, as a &lt;i&gt; result &lt;&#x2F;i&gt; of it being so painfully uninspired that many of the tropes are interesting to people who have never read fantasy books. However, if you read the books with an educated eye (or one that&#x27;s seen basically any amount of other fantasy pieces), you will swiftly see a clichéd tale in which virtually nothing interesting happens. Yes, they have their highlights, but on the whole, &lt;i&gt; J.K. Rowling is a mediocre writer at best. &lt;&#x2F;i&gt; At least in my eyes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what&#x27;s that all got to do with &lt;i&gt;my&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; interests? I couldn&#x27;t give a flying fuck about some shitty book series that got way too popular, mostly because that happens so often that it&#x27;s not worth worrying about anymore, so why am I talking about this? &lt;br&gt;
Well, dear reader, as I&#x27;m sure that you&#x27;re frightfully aware, J.K. Rowling is a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;jk_rowling&#x2F;status&#x2F;1269382518362509313&quot;&gt;transphobic arsehole&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Now, I&#x27;m not wishing to bring anything too particularly spicy to the table here, but shockingly, when somebody is against not only my &lt;i&gt;own&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; identity, but one that is widespread across the globe, especially with a platform as elevated as her own, I&#x27;m not too well pleased by it. When such a bitch then goes on to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;jk_rowling&#x2F;status&#x2F;1462758324177444870&quot;&gt;say that trans activists attempted to doxx her&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; whilst her address is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;duckduckgo.com&#x2F;?t=ffab&amp;q=jk+rowling+address&amp;ia=web&quot;&gt;easily accessible common fucking knowledge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, that&#x27;s when it just gets depressing. I&#x27;m glad that I&#x27;m not one of the countless LGBTQ+ fans of Harry Potter whose world&#x27;s been shattered by this; no, I&#x27;m just depressed by the fact that there are still legions of fuck-knockers who are willing to defend the &lt;i&gt;literal billionaire&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;, and the futility of this very post. Christ knows that we can&#x27;t really change her mind, because her mind is already set. People who believe in these sorts of ideals are hardwired to be closed-minded, and simply cannot be changed. Whether this is due to their fragile egos not allowing them to empower anyone outside of themselves or their friends, their stubborn stupidity and inability to accept reality, or some other third thing is entirely up to your own discretion. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
But... still, there&#x27;s got to be a catch. There&#x27;s countless transphobes around, why am I picking on specifically Jack-off Kunt Rowling? Well, &lt;a href=https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.videogameschronicle.com&#x2F;features&#x2F;hogwarts-legacy&#x2F;&gt;because there&#x27;s a Harry Potter game coming out&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m shouting into the void here, practically speaking, but in the event that anyone does read this, please, absolutely do not purchase this game. You can pirate it, pirate away, but do not support this, whether through money or through streaming it or what have you - she simply doesn&#x27;t deserve any of it. Amazingly, the game is attempting to separate itself from the established canon, likely as a get-out-of-jail-free card, to abscond themselves of all relation or agreement with her standpoints, but so long as the Harry Potter brand is attached, &lt;i&gt;avoid it&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;. If you buy this game, or any other Harry Potter (or Wizarding World or Dumbledore&#x27;s Funtime Gangbang or whatever the fuck it&#x27;s called now) merch for that matter, you&#x27;re engaging in the exact kind of mindless consumerism that gives idiots such as J.K. Rowling the platforms and obscene wealth to bleat these poisonous ideologies unto their masses of fans. Save the money, get something better by cool people. Save up for &lt;i&gt;Elden Ring&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;. Buy an indie game. Fuck, spend the money on bricks to smash together, it&#x27;ll be an infinitely less harmful and more engaging experience than anything the Wizarding Wank could conjure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to write this in order to vent the frustrations I held with the whole debacle. Especially with many of my friends previously being fans of Harry Potter, who have simply divorced the series from their interests - these people had Harry Potter, whether it be the books or movies, to help them through hard times, gave them good times, helped them make good friends, and all that fun stuff. Ironically, most of them seem to attribute the series to only helping them be &lt;i&gt;more&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; tolerant of people, as opposed to deciding to act maliciously towards them based on their identity. All in all, J.K. Rowling is bad. Play fuckin.. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wizard101.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Wizard 101&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; instead. Literally better Harry Potter.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add.: Ironically enough, as I was checking through this before I posted it, Pink Triangle by Weezer came on from my playlist. That&#x27;s pretty damn funny to me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Fuck Windows. *</title>
		<published>2021-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/fuckwindows/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/fuckwindows/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;* Legacy blog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows has been seen as the major mainstream OS since it&#x27;s inception in 1985, basically becoming an overnight success, only growing in popularity and usefulness with each iteration. This was, at first, deservedly so; Windows 95, 98 and XP were all widely used operating systems, making the once arcane world of computing accessible to a new audience, whilst not skimping on useful features for experienced power users. And all was good for this period of bliss.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then Vista hit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The release of Project Longhorn, released as Windows Vista, is the first in a long, long line of baffling, annoying, and downright stupid decisions from Microsoft. Upon release on January 30th 2007, it was immediately lambasted for its &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;jMvn6B6avrk&quot;&gt;instability&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, its high RAM usage, and general propensity to dick the user about with widgets and other such additions that were enabled by default. And these additions were predicted to work on less than &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thetimes.co.uk&#x2F;article&#x2F;windows-revamp-too-advanced-for-most-pcs-9x9jmjgwvpt&quot;&gt;5% of Britain&#x27;s PCs prior to release,&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; despite Microsoft &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.eweek.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;will-your-pc-run-windows-vista&#x2F;&quot;&gt;being adamant&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that &amp;quot;nuh uh! It&#x27;ll totally run&amp;quot;. The blatant lies told, hilariously, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.pcworld.idg.com.au&#x2F;article&#x2F;199744&#x2F;lawyers_even_microsoft_confused_over_vista_marketing&#x2F;&quot;&gt;landed them in court&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; wherein a Microsoft product manager stumbled on his words, effectively proving that the &#x27;Vista-Compatible&#x27; sticker was a load of old bollocks. Pair this with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;web.archive.org&#x2F;web&#x2F;20060909162825&#x2F;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.itwire.com.au&#x2F;content&#x2F;view&#x2F;5450&#x2F;53&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the frankly absurd pricing points,&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and it wasn&#x27;t hard to see that Microsoft had shifted from being &amp;quot;that company &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;FOl94fO78nk&quot;&gt;what gave me Weezer with my &#x27;95 install disc&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to yet another money-grubbing corporation who wanted money, and wanted it without concern for the end user. This would unfortunately mark the beginning of a slow, gradual death of a once-prosperous OS, and it&#x27;s transformation into a glorified bloatware bootloader.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img 
    style=&quot;display: block; 
           margin-left: auto;
           margin-right: auto;
           width: 70%;&quot;
    src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;articles&#x2F;b2&#x2F;weezmen.jpg&quot; 
    alt=&quot;Buddy Holly&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;img&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
What&#x27;s with these homies dissing my girl?
&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a few years to the release of Windows 7, on October 22, 2009: finally! A return to form following the prior three years of bugs, bluescreens and bollocks. It was bliss; it had a sleek, new look, including many features which we now take for granted being introduced (such as the ability to pin programs to the taskbar), a complete performance boost, a retooling of the Aero framework, and generally, it was an upgrade. Windows 7 was a frankly amazing step up from the dogwater Vista - so much so that back in yonder days, I took the plunge of learning how to make a boot USB of the OS and installing it on my shitty Toshiba Satellite M305D-S4829 laptop, at the ripe wee age of 6.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, even back then, I was a fuckin&#x27; nerd.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, point is, 7 was (and frankly still is) a stellar operating system. Unfortunately, this was the last good OS made by Microsoft, as a mere 3 years later, on October 26th 2012, Microsoft released Windows 8. Hahhh, God, they sure fuckin&#x27; released it, in the same way one releases a turd from their arse. Sorry, I&#x27;m just employing the same level of crudeness in my writing as Microsoft did with this... whatever the fuck you want to call it. Not a desktop operating system, that&#x27;s for bloody certain. What happened here?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows 7 was wonderful; it was simplistic, yet still had the power user features, it could be themed and skinned, you could actually use the fucking thing without it telling you to install Candy Crush every five goddamned seconds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows 8 was a turning point for Microsoft. It was a pivot back into the stupidity they had promised to no longer indulge with Vista, having all of it&#x27;s hallmarks, such as its over-use of RAM, annoying widgets and instability issues. But! Most wonderful at all, was the entirely unnecessary re-invention of the wheel!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img 
    style=&quot;display: block; 
           margin-left: auto;
           margin-right: auto;
           width: 70%;&quot;
    src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;articles&#x2F;b2&#x2F;binbows8.png&quot; 
    alt=&quot;michaelsoft&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;img&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;d-vB8qdNSYc?t=15&gt;&quot;My computer is not a phone... what is this shit?&quot;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
-Vinesauce Joel
&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the feature that everybody knows and is extremely fucking confused by at the very least, the Windows 8 Start Menu redesign. I shouldn&#x27;t have to explain exactly why this is a problem, but allow me to break it down somewhat.
This is a needless implementation of touchscreen design philosophies on a desktop OS, presumably made due to the fact that it would be easier to cross-integrate with the new Windows Phone 8, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Windows_Phone_8#Core&quot;&gt;which had switched to the same kernel as the desktop-based version of Windows.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; And instead of putting effort into simply having similar visual languages with optimizations and tweaks depending on the device you were on, similar to Apple, they decided: &amp;quot;why bother?&amp;quot; Why not just use the same huge fuck-off tiles you&#x27;d see on a phone that make using the Start Tile system a complete chore because you have to drag your mouse 15 miles across to hover over a different app? Why not make the window captions humongous? Why not integrate our own new Store so that we can make even more money? Ooh, actually, whilst we&#x27;re on, why don&#x27;t we use that Store in the Start Menu in order to push the user ads every time they boot their PC? That way, we can get lucrative advertising money!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&#x27;s all this ultimately boils down to; money. Corporate greed. The rich wanting all the dosh in the world. And all of it without lifting a finger.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had already bounced back from a similar situation with Vista; release the darling XP, then take a shit and rake in the dough. The trajectory was set to be identical here - release Windows 7, the ultimate Microsoft OS, and then release Windows 8, one of the worst desktop operating systems, second only to.. fuckin&#x27; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=YX5Sm0_aIo0&quot;&gt;TempleOS,&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; I guess.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security flaws, horrible design, the fucking ads, the constant telemetry; it all added up to make a terrible, terrible operating system. Windows 8.1 was slated as some sort of major release, too, which.. no? The only things that it really did was let us see our desktop on login instead of the Start Menu, which is good, but not enough to warrant calling it it&#x27;s own thing. Windows 8.1 was given the exact same press bunkum as 7 had behind it; &amp;quot;promises to address issues that users had on launch&amp;quot;. And so, the pieces were all in play for the new Microsoft business plan:
Step 1: Release the OS. Doesn&#x27;t matter if it&#x27;s terrible.
Step 2: Watch the money roll in from people who don&#x27;t know any better.
Step 3: Get critically panned.
Step 4: &amp;quot;Fix&amp;quot; your OS by adding features that should have been there since launch (or were in prior OSes)
Step 5: Get critical acclaim back.
Step 6: Watch even more money roll in.
Step 7: Eventually decide to make a new money generator-sorry, OS.
Step 8: Push obnoxious messages to force a user into upgrading.
Step 9: End support for the older, superior OSes in order to definitely ensure the user into upgrading.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this was exactly what ended up happening with 8.1, too; they would go on to release Windows 10, with even more telemetry, even more RAM usage (up to 4GB of idle used by solely the OS), and a new fun one - disk throttling! Yes, if you run Windows on an HDD as opposed to an SSD, your disk will throttle like mad, and it may even sometimes lead to your OS just entirely freezing for anywhere from seconds to minutes at a time! Isn&#x27;t that wonderful? Isn&#x27;t it great to hear that your OS is so extremely bloated, so taxing on hardware that merely running the OS by itself is enough to strain it? Keep in mind, no prior Windows versions had this issue - not even Vista. If it can ever be said that your OS has something wrong with it that Windows &amp;quot;watch me shit my pants&amp;quot; Vista doesn&#x27;t, you have fucked up bigstyle, my trans-national corporate chum.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows 10 also brought with it the dreaded curse. You know exactly what scenario to envision; middle of a round in CS, you&#x27;re about to absolutely pound the one remaining enemy&#x27;s bussy with that wonderful AK one-tap you&#x27;d been practicing, you&#x27;re poised, you&#x27;re ready, your finger hovering over the 5 key, ready to plant just to rub the salt in the wound..! And then, just as you see the first emerging pixels of the CT peaking you, the game closes. What!? And then, your screen turns to a solid colour with white text upon it. You hold your head in your hands as your magnificent game plan is scuppered, sending an angered video message of your predicament to your team who were wondering where you disappeared to, who all relate when they, too, read those dreaded words:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img 
    style=&quot;display: block; 
           margin-left: auto;
           margin-right: auto;
           width: 70%;&quot;
    src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;articles&#x2F;b2&#x2F;binbowsupdate.png&quot; 
    alt=&quot;updato&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;img&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
Aw, for fuck&#x27;s sakes!
&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automatic fucking updates. I&#x27;m not even gonna write anything on this - even people who give Bill Gates gobjobs won&#x27;t attempt to argue that these are one of the most annoying things to ever come out of Windows.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, you know, there is always an alternative. There&#x27;s an easier, better way. A way that allows for you to have whatever features you want, strip the ones you don&#x27;t, make everything look the way you fancy, and cost absolutely nothing except disk space. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lutris.net&#x2F;games&#x2F;candy-crush-saga&#x2F;&quot;&gt;If you want, you can even still play Candy Crush.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#x27;s right, motherfucker, this is a Linux shill now! Bet you couldn&#x27;t have guessed that from the URL of this post being obliquely anti-Windows.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you, yes you, can try Linux today! My personal recommendation is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manjaro.org&#x2F;downloads&#x2F;official&#x2F;kde&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Manjaro with the KDE Desktop Environment,&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as it allows you to have a Windows-esque interface by default, just for you to test the waters, to see if you like it. Hell, if you want, you don&#x27;t even have to install it right away, you can just run it in a testing environment from the USB you plonk the media on. And? No automatic updates. When you do update, too, no need to drop everything and pencil yourself in for 20 minutes of finding something else to do whilst waiting; you can just keep using your OS. Keep using your programs. Everything just keeps going.
If you&#x27;re concerned for the environment, too, Linux uses a lot less power at idle times than Windows could ever hope to. It uses a lot less of everything, really - RAM, CPU and GPU usage are a fraction of their Windows competition, leaving you more resources to do whatever you want.
Wanna play games? Get a load of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lutris.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Lutris,&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a launcher that allows you to install games yourself, or through using community-made profiles. And I&#x27;m sure you&#x27;ve heard of Valve&#x27;s Proton by now - their own suite that contains a modified version of WINE in order to act as a compatibility layer between Linux and Windows. In non-jargon speak, that basically means it makes your Windows shite work on Linux. Now, of course, there are exceptions; anti-cheats such as EasyAntiCheat (e.g. Fortnite) and Battleye (e.g. Destiny 2) have minimal Proton support as of writing, although this may change with the release of the Steam Deck, as developers may choose to opt in to allow for more players to experience their games via Linux.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, if you want to escape the clutches of Microsoft, take back some of your privacy (as much as you can with the modern internet anyway), and learn some new stuff, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manjaro.org&#x2F;downloads&#x2F;official&#x2F;kde&#x2F;&quot;&gt;install Linux.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; It&#x27;s free - again, it costs nothing but the disk space you install it on, and it doesn&#x27;t even need to cost that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Also, this should go without saying, but if you use Windows, I don&#x27;t look down on you or anything. Everybody has their preferences. Like me: my preference is that I very, very much dislike Windows.)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Finding Yakuza *</title>
		<published>2021-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/findingyakuza/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jellyfoxx.github.io/blog/findingyakuza/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;* Legacy blog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryu Ga Gotoku, otherwise known in my ASDA-shopping, pork-pie eating, tea drinking tongue as Yakuza.
Yakuza is a series with which I have become increasingly infatuated over the last couple of years; it initially began merely as me saying &amp;quot;oh haha look at that funny bloke exploding that other bloke&#x27;s skull with a bench&amp;quot; quite some years ago when I first saw &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=yrvKjrPgeyM&quot;&gt;Yahtzee&#x27;s ZP episode&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Yakuza 4, and that was it on the matter. At least, for about... hm, seven-ish years? And then that song, that bloody song had to just get popular and send me down this rabbithole properly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This song... it just immediately landed with me. The sombre subject matter, covered with a layer of that dramatic cheese from the &amp;quot;wah-wah&amp;quot; of the backing track, and who was that sexy fuckin&#x27; voice, suave and deep, tickling my cochleas with a velvet-coated finger? Due to my obsession with this new &amp;quot;dame da ne&amp;quot; thing, I took to the internet: what have I just found, and God, how do I get my hands on it? I looked into it, finding the song was, in fact, not called simply Dame Da Ne (dame dane?), but Baka Mitai. Baka Mitai is the first and last time I have been thankful for the impact a meme has had on me for any longer than five minutes, as it would be the spark that lit the explosive powder keg that is my undying affection for (a good majority) of this series. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;1000px&quot; height=&quot;750px&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube-nocookie.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;ZSBnCOGj2t4&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;Who is this illustrious specimen of manhood displayed before my eyes?&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having found Baka Mitai, my discovery of it&#x27;s origin followed sharply. It was from a game called Yakuza 0. Oh, yes, I recalled, I vaguely remember those games! Yahtzee did &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=wudc8nOSScU&quot;&gt;a few&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=tK5iAzRWR_k&quot;&gt;videos&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=e_AD1aBkDH4&quot;&gt;on&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=xSL7JnnDYik&quot;&gt;that series&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. That&#x27;s the one with the bloke who smashes skulls with spare bikes! I wonder what that game&#x27;s on? And to my overwhelming joy, there it was: available on Steam. Which meant, me being a broke motherfucker, it was time to sail the high seas and get my Japanese concussion-gifting service off the ground with a bottle of rum and a yo-ho-ho. I set away the download, looked at the Steam screenshots, and even before going anywhere close to playing the thing, I was in utter love.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sexy men. The two extremely sexy men on the Steam page. The combat. The fact that you could use practically any part of the environment to aid the combat! The music! The campy, melodramatic crime drama story being set up! The Japanese setting! It was all enough to make a dumb girl like me feel like she was younger again, harkening back to fond memories of clutching a game&#x27;s box and eyeballing every last nook and cranny of the box before I would excitedly clamber out of the car and chuck the disc into my PS2. Whilst I would have preferred a physically tangible way of thumbing through a limited pool of information to get me hyped for the game, the Steam page and the comments on the YouTube upload of the trailer for the original PS4 localisation got me feeling that tingle in my chest, that stupid smirk crossing my happy face, and joyfully humming along to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;ApreCAQiZ4w&quot;&gt;the music I had heard in the advertisements.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; I absolutely could not wait for that 350 KB&#x2F;s download from some Russian site to finish so I could have the time of my life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the time of my life I certainly fucking had. I truly cannot describe the pure joy and happiness that resulted from that first boot of Yakuza 0. The SEGA logo fucking flashbanging me wasn&#x27;t needed, but it most certainly assured I was awake. Following my rude sensory destruction, I saw five words make a phrase that, like the very game I was about to play, was a somewhat serious message wrapped in an extremely tongue-in-cheek, campy presentation:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img 
    style=&quot;display: block; 
           margin-left: auto;
           margin-right: auto;
           width: 70%;&quot;
    src=&quot;&#x2F;assets&#x2F;articles&#x2F;b1&#x2F;ryuag.jpg&quot; 
    alt=&quot;Real Yakuza Use a Gamepad.&quot;
    title=&quot;Real Yakuza Use a Gamepad.&quot;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;img&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;The best splash screen in gaming, bar none.&lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh my fucking God, that&#x27;s hilarious. And I&#x27;ll be damned if it&#x27;s not still funny, even after having seen it potentially in excess of a hundred times! And the same can be said of Yakuza 0 itself; even after my extensive experience of Yakuza, even after having played all 6 Kiryu Saga games (including the Kiwami remakes), even after having played Dead Souls, even after a new protagonist entirely has been introduced... I love it. I love everything about Yakuza 0. In fact, in retrospect, upon replaying all of the games, Yakuza 0 is the peak of the series, and everything else after that point can fairly safely be written off with a single exception: Kiwami, solely because it&#x27;s a remake of the first Yakuza in the Yakuza 0 engine - therefore making it absolutely kickarse since it&#x27;s more 0 with content added to the original framework it had that fits incredibly well into the series, and is a perfect supplementary piece to Yakuza 0. Perhaps not the definitive experience, and it certainly has it&#x27;s issues, but it&#x27;s an amazing way for new, budding fans to continue into the series hot off of the heels of having played 0.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entries following this such as the depressingly boring Yakuza 6: The Song of Life, the execrable cash-grab of Yakuza Kiwami 2, and the mediocre-at-best and frankly overrated Yakuza: Like a Dragon (so Yakuza: Yakuza*, then?) are all downhill, and presumably after the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tojodojo.com&#x2F;rgg-studio-announce-new-leadership-and-departures&#x2F;&quot;&gt;unfortunate departure of Toshiro Nagoshi,&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; this trend will only continue. Christ, do I hope to be proven wrong, but I have rock-bottom hopes for the promise of &amp;quot;bland character who already had his pitiful arc resolved in the last game goes global&amp;quot; proposed for Like a Dragon 2: This Time We Added Even More Dragons.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, my opinions on the diminishing quality of the series as of the present (i.e. when I&#x27;m writing this) are opinions that are best kept for another time, as this post is meant to celebrate my relationship with Yakuza, the anniversary of the first time I finished 0, and to act as a letter of proposal to Goro Majima. I wanna be raw-dogged by the Mad Dog, dude.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* And yes, I am aware that it&#x27;s subtitled The Whereabouts of Light and Darkness in Japan, shhhh.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
